marksandspencer.ie 2017-12-20

# Privacy Policy

## IMPORTANT – PLEASE READ CAREFULLY

**Marks & Spencer is committed to respecting the privacy rights of visitors to its website. This privacy policy explains how we collect, store and use personal data about you when you browse www.marksandspencer.ie (the "Website"), shop with us or otherwise provide your personal data to us. These terms will apply regardless of how the Website is accessed and will cover any technologies or devices by which Marks and Spencer (Ireland) Limited make the Website available to You. It provides you with details about the types of personal data that we collect from you, how we use your personal data and the rights you have to control our use of your personal data.**

**You must read this privacy policy carefully and we recommend that you print and retain a copy for your future reference. By accessing, browsing or otherwise using this Website, you confirm that you have read, understood and agree to this privacy policy in its entirety. If you do not agree to this privacy policy in its entirety, you must not use this Website.**

## Who we are

Marks and Spencer Ireland (Limited) is a company registered in Ireland (Company Number 16855) whose registered office is at 24-29 Mary Street, Dublin 1, Ireland. Registered VAT number is GB 975 1954 76.

M&S is part of the group of companies which are wholly or partly owned by Marks and Spencer plc (“M&S Group”). M&S Group includes other associated M&S companies from time-to-time. M&S may communicate your data to other members of the M&S Group who will also act as data controllers for the purposes set out in this Policy.

We respect your right to privacy and will only process personal data you provide to us in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 and other applicable privacy laws.

If you have any questions about how we collect, store and use personal data, or if you have any other privacy-related questions, please contact us by any of the following means:

Marks and Spencer (Ireland) Limited. Registered office: 24-29 Mary Street, Dublin 1, Ireland. Registered number: 16855.

Email us at customer@service.marksandspencer.ie  
Telephone us on 00353 632072812

We do not and will not knowingly collect information from any unsupervised person under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, you must not use this Website or submit any personal data to us unless you have the consent of, and are supervised by, a parent or guardian.

## The personal data we collect about you

When you make purchases from Marks & Spencer (including purchases made in-store, over the phone, or via our catalogue order forms or this Website) we may collect the following personal data about you :

  * your name, age and sex;
  * your billing and delivery postal addresses, phone, fax and e-mail details;
  * where you have registered with us, your user name and password;
  * where you place an order with us, your payment card details;
  * your communication and shopping preferences;
  * your browsing and on line shopping activities; and
  * your date of birth.

We may also collect some or all of the above personal data about you when you access and browse this Website including when you sign up to receive Marks & Spencer newsletters. We may also collect some or all of this personal data from third parties who have your consent to pass your details to us.

Marks & Spencer (and third party data processors acting on our behalf) may collect, store and process your personal data:

  * to make this Website available to you and to provide you with content which is tailored to your individual tastes;
  * to maintain any registered account that you hold with us;
  * with your agreement, to contact you (including by SMS and e-mail) about promotional offers and products and services which we think may interest you and for customer satisfaction and market research purposes;
  * to provide our goods and services to you and for associated purposes, including verifying your identity;
  * for research, analysis, testing, monitoring, risk management and administrative purposes; and
  * for any related purposes, or where we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information (including for crime and fraud prevention and related purposes).

We also process your payment card details in order to complete any purchase that you make through this Website and, in certain instances, disclose your personal data to third party credit reference agencies to perform credit checks against you. When you place an order with us, we may offer to retain your payment card details for your convenience to save you having to re-enter these details on a future occasion. However, if you prefer that we do not maintain these details, you can go to 'My Account', click on ‘Edit or delete a credit card’ and delete any card information that we hold about you.

In addition, we may collect anonymised details about visitors to our Website for the purposes of aggregate statistics or reporting purposes. However, no single individual will be identifiable from the anonymised details that we collect for these purposes.

Except as set out in this privacy policy, we will not disclose, sell or rent your personal data to any third party. If you do consent but later change your mind, you may contact us and we will cease any such activity.

In the event that a third party acquires all or part of our business and/or assets, we may disclose your personal data to that third party in connection with the acquisition. Furthermore, we reserve the right to disclose your personal data to third parties as part of any business or asset sale carried out because M&S or other M&S Group companies has gone into insolvency or any similar situation, but only where lawful and compliant with the Data Protection Act 1998. We may also disclose your personal data where necessary to comply with applicable law or an order of a governmental or law enforcement body.

## E-mail newsletter preferences and text alerts

We provide you with the ability to control whether or not to receive e-mail newsletters. To unsubscribe from an email newsletter, please click the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email newsletter you have received from M&S. To stop text alerts, please follow the stop instructions at the bottom of any text alert you have received from M&S.

## Personalised banner advertising

If you browse this Website you may receive personalised banner advertisements whilst browsing other reputable websites. We are committed to providing you with information on products and offers which are relevant to you. Any banner advertisements you receive will relate to products which have been viewed whilst browsing this Website on your computer or other device. This service is provided by M&S via a reputable third party specialist provider, through the use of ‘cookies’ placed on your computer or other device (see further information on the use of cookies in the section below). Cookies can be removed or disabled altogether - see below for further information.

## Targeted updates and marketing

If you have agreed that we can contact you for marketing purposes we may send you emails and other communications relating to products and services which we think will be of interest and relevance to you as an individual. We do this by monitoring the browsing and on-line shopping habits of customers and providing them with information on products they have viewed and related products.

## International transfers

We transfer some personal data that we collect from you to third party data processors located in countries that are outside of the European Economic Area. Where we do so we will ensure that your personal data is subject to the same level of protection as when processed within the EEA and that such transfers are fully compliant with applicable privacy laws. In most cases our processors will be required to enter into the model contractual clauses which have been approved for such purposes by the European Commission. Alternatively, some of our data processors based in the US have signed up to the Safe Harbor scheme overseen by the US Federal Trade Commission.

## Cookies

## Cookie Policy

## What are cookies?

This website uses cookies to collect information. Cookies are small data files which are placed on your computer or other mobile or handheld device (such as smart ‘phones or ‘tablets’) as you browse this website. They are used to ‘remember’ when your computer or device accesses this website. The cookies are essential to the effective operation of our website and to enable to you shop with us online. Cookies are also used to tailor the products and services offered and advertised to our customers, both on this website and elsewhere.

## Information collected

Some cookies collect information about browsing and purchasing behaviour by people who access this website via the same computer or device. This includes information about pages viewed, products purchased and the customer journey around a website. We do not, however, use cookies to collect or record information on users’ name, address or other contact details. M&S is able to use cookies to monitor individual customer browsing and purchasing behaviour but third parties are not able to identify customers using cookies.

## Who sets the cookies?

The cookies stored on your computer or other device when you access this website are set by M&S, our suppliers who partner with us to help deliver a high quality website and on-line shopping experience, and other third parties. Some cookies are set by or on behalf of M&S and are necessary to enable customers to a make purchases on our website.  
Cookies may also be set by third parties who participate with us in affiliate marketing programmes. The most important such third parties are Criteo, Transversal and Rich Relevance who broadcast banner advertisements on behalf of M&S and a number of other reputable companies. None of these third parties collect any personal data from which they would be able to identify individual customers.

## What are cookies used for?

The main purposes for which cookies are used are:-  
1\. For technical purposes essential to effective operation of website, particularly in relation to on-line transactions.  
2\. To drive M&S marketing, particularly banner advertisements and targeted updates which are explained in more detail elsewhere in the Privacy Policy.  
3\. To enable M&S to collect information about the browsing and shopping habits and activities of customers, including to monitor the success of campaigns, competitions etc.  
4\. To enable M&S meet its contractual obligations to make payments to third parties when a product is purchased by someone who has visited our website from a site operated by those parties.

## How do I disable cookies?

If you want to disable cookies you need to change your website browser settings to reject cookies. How to do this will depend on the browser you use and we provide further detail below on how to disable cookies for the most popular browsers:-

## For Microsoft Internet Explorer:

  1. Choose the menu “tools” then “Internet Options”
  2. Click on the “privacy” tab
  3. Select the setting the appropriate setting

## For Mozilla firefox:

  1. Choose the menu “tools” then “Options”
  2. Click on the icon “privacy”
  3. Find the menu “cookie” and select the relevant options

## For Opera 6.0 and further:

  1. Choose the menu Files”> “Preferences”
  2. Privacy

## What happens if I disable cookies?

This depends on which cookies you disable, but in general the site may not operate properly if cookies are switched off. If you only disable 3rd party cookies you will not be prevented from making purchases on this site. If you disable all cookies you will be unable to complete a purchase on this site.

## Security Policy

We use Internet standard encryption technology ("SSL" or "Secure Socket Layer" technology) to encode personal data that you send to us when placing an order through the Website. To check that you are in a secure area of the Website before sending personal data to us, please look at the bottom right of your website browser and check that it displays an image of a closed padlock or an unbroken key.

However, please note that whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard the personal data that you provide to us, no transmission over the Internet can ever be guaranteed secure. Consequently, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data that you transfer over the Internet to us.

If you are using a computer or terminal in a public location, we recommend that you always log out and close the website browser when you complete an online session for your security. In addition we recommend that you take the following security measures to enhance your online safety:

  * Keep your account passwords private. Remember, anybody who knows your password may access your account.
  * When creating a password, use at least 8 characters. A combination of letters and numbers is best. Do not use dictionary words, your name, email address, or other personal data that can be easily obtained. We also recommend that you frequently change your password. You can do this by going to ‘My Account’ and clicking ‘Change name, email or password’.
  * Avoid using the same password for multiple online accounts.

## Spoof/false e-mails

We will never ask you to confirm any account or credit card details via email. If you receive an email claiming to be from M&S or other M&S Group companies asking you to do so, please ignore it and do not respond.

## Your rights

You have the following rights:

  * the right to ask what personal data that we hold about you at any time (aside from the reasonable costs of reproducing the data we will not charge you for providing this information to you and to receive a response within 21 days);
  * the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you free of charge.
  * the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you;
  * the right to have any personal data we hold about you erased or blocked within 40 days of the receipt of such a request from you; and
  * the right to request us to cease processing your personal data where such processing is likely to cause substantial distress or damage.

If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the contact details specified above. However, if you wish to unsubscribe from e-mail marketing communications that we send you, you can most easily do this by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any e-mail newsletter we have sent to you or, alternatively, by visiting our e-mail newsletter preference centre.

## Third party sites

This Website may contain links to other websites operated by third parties. Please note that this privacy policy applies only to the personal data that we collect through this Website and we cannot be responsible for personal data that third parties may collect, store and use through their website.. You should always read the privacy policy of each website you visit carefully.

## Updates to this policy

Our privacy policy was last amended in August 2011. Please check this page regularly to find out about updates to the policy.
